why won't monetary success save Black people? Why is it that, you know, just having fancy jobs or
just having economics in the community, like, why won't that save Black people? Because I know that
when I put this up, people were like, so you're saying that Black people can't be successful?
It's like, nah, that's not what I'm saying at all. But I think that what we deem success
is a very important part of the conversation in terms of how we
are able to help our communities. Would you agree? Oh, absolutely. I mean, I think our
understanding of freedom, our understanding of excellence, of success, of healing, all these
words that we throw around, they got to be rooted in the past, the present and the future.
You know, it has to be, that's what Imagine Freedom is about. It's a continuum.
When you think about our ancestors, I mean, enslaved Africans, colonized Africans, I believe
they thought about who they were before the oppressor came. They thought about who they
were before the arrival of colonization and slave ships. You know, so basically, who were
they before the infiltration of white supremacy and capitalism? And so there was a village system
there. There was a system of communal values and communal ways of life. I mean, where you
have poor people who have nothing, but lack for nothing, because the village takes care
of them. You know, and so I do think that there's a way in which our people have always known
the answers, you know, have had ancestral wisdom. Even indigenous people on American soil have
had this ancestral wisdom, right? So I think we got to lean into the past. We got to look
at the present and say, right now we have a form of hero worship and celebrity worship
that is unlike any other generation. We worship billionaires. We worship multimillionaires.
And that is not where our people have been historically. Historically, our people just wanted
safety. You know, they wanted freedom of movement. They wanted the basics of life. They wanted love.
They wanted intimacy. They wanted possibility for their children. We've transformed those
basic dreams and suggested that our ancestors wanted mansions, that they wanted empire, that
they wanted global brands. It's not true. You know what that's not meant to me? It sounds
like that our ancestors want what their oppressors want. Yes. Yes. That, I mean, that's my fundamental
argument, right? That our proximity to power, our proximity to wealth has one normalized it
and made us think that it's easy to become a billionaire and a millionaire. And it's not. It's
not, it's not, it's not, it's not common in America or anywhere else in the world. You know,
the top 1% cannot be normalized as what everybody should be doing. You know, so our folks are no
longer just striving for a middle-class existence, but they're striving to be multimillionaires.
So we have now made white supremacy the benchmark of our success.